Every dream has a price.
Wall Street is a crime, drama film directed by Oliver Stone.
A young and impatient stockbroker is willing to do anything to get to the top, including trading on illegal inside
information taken through a ruthless and greedy corporate raider, whom takes the youth under his wing.
Gordon Gekko, played by Michael Douglas.
Bud Fox, played by Charlie Sheen.
Carl Fox, played by Martin Sheen.
Darien Taylor, played by Daryl Hannah.
Marvin, played by John C. McGinley.
Lou Mannheim, played by Hal Holbrook.
Wall Street is a 1987 American crime drama film directed and co-written by Oliver Stone,
which stars Michael Douglas, Charlie Sheen, Daryl Hannah, and Martin Sheen.
The film tells the story of Bud Fox (C.
Sheen), a young stockbroker who becomes involved with Gordon Gekko
(Douglas), a wealthy, unscrupulous corporate raider.
Stone made the film as a tribute to his father, Lou Stone,
a stockbroker during the Great Depression.
The character of Gekko is said to be a composite of several people, including Dennis Levine,
Ivan Boesky, Carl Icahn, Asher Edelman, Michael Milken and Stone himself.
The character of Sir Lawrence Wildman, meanwhile, was modelled on
British financier and corporate raider Sir James Goldsmith.
Originally, the studio wanted Warren Beatty to play Gekko, but he was not interested;
Stone, meanwhile, wanted Richard Gere, but Gere passed on the role.
The film was well received among major film critics.
Douglas won the Academy Award for Best Actor, and the film has come to be seen as the archetypal portrayal of 1980s excess, with Douglas' character declaring that "greed, for lack of a better word, is good." It has also proven influential
in inspiring people to work on Wall Street, with Sheen, Douglas, and Stone commenting over the years how people still approach them and say that they became stockbrokers because of their respective characters in the film.
Stone and Douglas reunited for a sequel titled Wall Street: Money Never
Sleeps, which was released theatrically on September 24, 2010.
The film explores themes of new york city, fraud, wall street, broker, finances.
The tone is emotional.